A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Administrative Functions, RG 4 FA1798
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Administration, 1983-2019; 1; 3.42 Cubic Feet 8 letter document boxes and 2 half-letter document boxes
  - Human Resources, 1983-2017; 1.3; 2.28 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes and 2 half-letter document boxes
    - Staffing, 1990-2017; 3.3
      - Transformation Grantmaking Toolkit, 2007 February 20-April 12 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        Includes Transformational Grant Summaries template and guide; transformational grant monitoring and reporting tools; a process map and highlights of expert interviews on transformational grantmaking.
      - STAR Award Program, 2007 July 26-2010 (Box 5, Folder 6)
        Knight File Number - 4677
        Background information on creation of a new staff recognition program, call STAR. Included are notes, presentations, emails, nomination forms for Action Award, Action Plus Award or President's Award, and winners for 2008-2010.
      - Planning & Executing Successful Meetings (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Knight File Number - 4383
        Quick Reference Guide Brochure and Instructor's Manual which provide directions and details on meeting preparation for administrative assistants.
      - Full Staff Meeting Agendas, 2013 March 19-2017 June 15 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        Knight File Number - 5147
        Restricted - Open 2028
        Agendas for quarterly full staff meeting. Meetings are held after the board meetings to provide staff with a general overview and initiate and program updates. A special off-site meeting was called to discuss the CEP Grantee Perception Report (October 2014). Also included is a memo from Terese Coudreaut re: Performance and Motivation at Knight Foundation - A Fresh Approach (August 20, 2015).
      - Staff Presentations, 2013-2015, 2013 January-2015 March 11 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        Knight File Number - 5325
        Restricted - Open 2026
        PowerPoint presentations: 1) Working Session to Craft 2013 Goals; 2) Write @ Knight, about peer reviewing; 3) Running Effective Meetings, about what it takes to run a successful meeting using technology; 4) FIU Grant Writing Certification Presentation; 5) A Guide to Engaging with an Independent Contractor; and 6) Charitable Purpose Handbook, which outlines ways KF grants can support Knight's mission while advancing charitable purpose.
      - Salesforce Sales Cloud Platform Implementation Project, 2014 April-June (Box 5, Folder 10)
        Knight File Number - 5376
        Salesforce application will allow KF staff to manage all KF constituents and track all interactions, participation in events and outreach activity. Included is a consulting services agreement with ACF Solutions, statement of work (pages 1-2 of 9 only), an agenda for implementation meetings, and an implementation requirements document.
      - Grant Due Diligence Deep Dive, 2014 June 26 (Box 5, Folder 11)
        Knight File Number - 5377
        Meeting was to explain the two "decision trees" created to explain the difference between fiscal agency versus fiscal sponsorship and when expenditure responsibility is and is not required.
      - Staff Health Screening, 2014 October 8 (Box 5, Folder 12)
        Knight File Number - 5452
        Notice encouraging KF staffers to undergo health screenings and flu shots in return for cash incentives.
      - Finance Associate Recruiting, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 13)
        Knight File Number - 5486
        Memo from Terese Coudreaut with the unusual request for internal candidates to quickly fill a Finance Department vacancy.
      - Office Moves, 2015 March 31-April 6 (Box 5, Folder 14)
        Knight File Number - 5604
        Memos from Terese Coudreaut and Susan Gomez with details on the office moves for KF Miami. Also included is a map with the new layout.
      - KForce Training, 2015 May (Box 6, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 5570
        PowerPoint presentations on the introduction of KForce (Administration and Staff Training), which will centralize contact, relationship and document management at Knight. Also included is a feedback report on the helpfulness of the KF training and memos outlining the training schedule subscription management and a memo re: Okta, a cloud-based resource that allows access to all KF computer resources, including KForce, Fluxx, Box and Slack.
      - Staff Memos, 2016 March 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Knight File Number - 5694
        Two staff memos: 1) Board meeting and Common Knowledge Logistics re: schedule of events during the March Board of Trustees meeting and 2) memo re: campaign intervention and lobbying which cautions KF staffers and trustees not to engage in partisan political activities on company time or using company resources.
      - Home Week, 2016 December 20 (Box 6, Folder 4)
        Knight File Number - 5750
        January 2017 Home Week agenda. Starting in 2017, all KF staff are required to gather quarterly to exchange information to leverage the range of expertise and ability across staff in service to support informed and engaged communities. The agenda includes time for all staff discussions and departmental and one-on-one meetings.
      - KForce Training- EFT & Address Update Process, 2017 January (Box 6, Folder 5)
        Knight File Number - 5869
        PowerPoint presentation and training on KForce and Work Place process to update Vendor EFT, vendor's address and how to find the GP Vendor ID in work Place.
      - Staff Presentations, Home Week Sessions, 2017 March-May (Box 6, Folder 6)
        Knight File Number - 5870
        All-staff discussion and Working Session on diversity, equity and inclusion, facilitated by The Race Matters Institute (RMI) to embark on an effort to improve our ability to consider, discuss and reflect in our work real understanding of issues of diversity, equity and inclusion. In order to provide critical context and foregrounding to the session, three pre-reading were assigned, The Curb-Cut Effect, by Angela Glover Blackwell, A Gardener's Tale, by Camara Jones and The Case for Reparations by Ta-Nehisi Coates. Also included is the May Home Week Agenda.
      - Prohibition of Unlawful Harassment, email discussion, 2017, 2017 November 29-30 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        Knight File Number - 5997
        Email discussion of the Foundation's Unlawful Harassment policy in light of the current events.
    - Strategic Planning, 2015; 3.4
      - Administration Strategy, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        Knight File Number - 5996
        Administration Strategy overview
  - Legal, 1990-2019; 1.4; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
    - John S. Knight Remainder Unitrust Hearing, 1999 June 8-2007 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 2136
      Court documents and summonses, e-mails, and notes pertaining to the hearings to reform the Knight Unitrust which would permit more flexible investments by the trust manager. The Knight Foundation, as the remainder beneficiary, had no objection.
    - James L. Knight Trust, 1993-2004 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
      Knight File Number - 6002
      Various documents pertaining to the James L. Knight Trust including: Receipt of Beneficiary and Refunding Agreement; Security and Pledge Agreement; Custodial Pledge; Property appraisal; Sale of Real Estate. In 2 folders.
    - Lease - One Biscayne Tower, 1990 July 9-2002 July 8 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 2135
      Original lease (copy) and first and fourth amendments to the lease (original) and other addenda.
    - Lease - First Union Financial Center, 2002 September 10-2010 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 2133
      Original, with amendments. Also included is a lease abstract and first amendment, dated 2010.
    - Office Space - Purchase or Lease, 2001 July 30-September 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 4356
      Booklet, prepared by Belinda Lawrence, provides background information about purchasing or leasing office space. Includes a survey of other foundations and information on available parcels in Miami.
    - Legal Briefing for Program Liaisons, 2002 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 4738
      Briefing was provided by Rod Petry, long time KF counsel. Topics for liaisons included: charitible exemptions, self-dealing, lobbying, and conflicts.
    - Information for Legal Opinion re: Media Challenge, 2008 August 11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 4365
      Documents (some from Archives sources) sent to Rod Petry, KF Legal Counsel, in order to obtain a legal opinion about former Knight Ridder newspapers as grantees. Includes: a list of contributions by newspapers to KF, 1950-1965 (from KF History); "KRI Stock Price and KF Asset History" (prepared by Juan Martinez); a list of trustees, 1998-2008, which indicates any relationship with KRI; and charts of board and committee meeting attendance, 2005-2007.
    - Agreement to Establish the Knight Foundation Miami Arts Initiative Fund, 2008 December (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 4676
      The Miami Arts Initiative Fund was a donor-advised fund at Dade Community Foundation, Inc. in which the DCF received a fee for administering the Fund for the Knight Foundation.
    - Board of Trustee Meeting - Executive Session re: KF Real Estate/Offices, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 4733
      Talking points, prepared by Belinda Lawrence, re: strategic options for office space - own vs. rent, location and costs.
    - Lease - Wachovia Financial Center, 2010 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 4757
      First Amendment to Lease which, among other provisions, extends the lease for the 33rd floor to December 31, 2020.
    - Draft PRI Documentation for News Challenge Winners 2010, 2010 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 5280
      Memo from Greenberg Traurig lawyer, Bruce Macdonough, concerning KF's program-related investments in Knight News Challenge winners.
    - Knight Investments, LLC, 2011 June 3-6 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 4989
      Limited Liability Agreement of Knight Investments, LLC, formed in Delaware, and its sole member, Knight Foundation.
    - Revised Grant Agreement, 2011 March 10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 4905
      Memo from Julie Brooks Nyquist, Grants Manager, outlining the newly revised grant agreement. The revised template reflects clearer language to communicate KF compliance terms with KF grantees, both financial and programmatic. Also included is a copy of the template.
    - Record of Donation of Electronic Equipment, 2014 May 15-18 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 5373
      Record of donation of $4,500 worth of computer equipment by KF to the South Florida Digital Alliance/Miami-Dade Broadband Coalition.
    - Disaster Recovery and Emergency Response Plans, 2015 June-2017 June (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 5742
      Two plans - Disaster Recovery and Response Plan and Emergency Response Procedures - developed by HR to respond to threats and catastrophic disturbances in the workplace.
    - Name Registration and Trademark, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 5998
      Registration for Knight Foundation, fictitious name registration State of Florida November 8, 2017. KF registered trademark design, U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, November 8, 2017.
    - U.S. Trademark Registrations, 2011 March 29-2017 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 4876
      1. Copy of the Registered Trademark for "entertainment services in the nature of live musical performances in class 41" awarded to KF for Random Act of Culture. 2. U.S. Trademark applications for the Knight Commission mark covered in class 9, 16, 36, and 41 3. U.S. Trademark application for the Knight Prototype Fund, class 41 4. U.S. Trademark application for John S. and James L. Knight Foundation, class 16, 41 5. Certificate of U.S. Service Mark Registration for Knight Foundation, class 35 6. U.S. Trademark application and registration for Knight Foundation, class 16, class 9, 36 and class 41 7. U.S. Trademark registration for Knight Enterprise Fund in class 36. 8. U.S. Trademark registration for John S. and James L. Knight Foundation in classes 6, 38, and 41. 9. Notice of publication for Knight Commission in classes 38 and 41. 10. Notice of allowance for Knight News Challenge mark in class 9, 16, 36 and 41. 11. Notice of publication for Knight Arts Challenge in class 36 and 41. 12. U.S. Trademark application for Knight Commission in class 36 13. Notice of allowances for Knight Commission in classes 38 & 41 and Knight News Challenge for class 41. 14. U.S. Trademark application for Knight Foundation in class 36. 15. Certificate of Registration for Knight Commission in classes 16 and 9. 16. Certificate of Registration for KF, KF logo, and KF KNIGHT FOUNDATION logo in Class 36.
    - Conflict of Interest, 2007 (Box 2)
      Knight File Number - 5282
      Memo and supporting documentation re: KF's revision of its conflict of interest policy to include employment engagements between Knight employees and grantees, board service and outside engagements by staff. Also included is an examination of the policies at KF peer foundations.
    - Conflict of Interest Reports, 2012-2019 (Box 2)
      Knight File Number - 5526
      Restricted - Open 2030
      Year end reports providing a listing of employee and trustee affiliations as part of Conflict of Interest reporting. Those of significant others/spouses are also listed. The 2014 and 2015, 2018 and 2019 reports also include sections listing possible benefit (yes or no), explanation of benefits, and how relation would be received ("possible appearance of influence", etc.). Reports are generated from the forms that employees and trustees file electronically each year.
    - Document requests and subpoenas, 2015-2019 (Box 2)
      Knight File Number - 5999
      Various legal requests, subpoenas for documents, 2015-2019
- Communications, 1943-2017; 2; 9.78 Cubic Feet 28 containers
  - Administrative Files, 1990-2016; 2.1; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
    Documents concerning Knight Foundation policies and public statements and requests for information and republishing rights from newspapers.
    - New Description of Knight Foundation, 1996 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 2413
      Memo to Knight Foundation staff from Larry Meyer re: revised statement of purpose for the Knight Foundation.
    - Akron Beacon Journal Article on Knight Foundation Funding, 1990 March 22-1997 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 2414
      Memos, correspondence, and newspaper articles re: preparation of an Akron Beacon Journal article on the Knight brothers' influence on Akron civic affairs and Knight Foundation funding for Akron. Larry Meyer worked with the Journal reporter to provide background information; Jerry Austen spoke on the record to him. The articles rely heavily on information from Charles Whited's biography of Jack Knight and quote trustees C.C. Gibson and John Ong.
    - Policy and Public Statement re: Knight Foundation Cities, 1997 September 23-October 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 2415
      Memos to Knight Foundation staff from Larry Meyer re: Knight Foundation cities and the board of trustees policy for funding vis-?-vis Knight-Ridder, Inc. acquisitions and divestitures.
    - Biography of John S. Knight -- Request to reprint, 1998 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 1075
      Request by Debora Van Tassel of the Akron Beacon Journal to reprint material from the biography of John S. Knight. Accepted by Larry Meyer, Communications Director.
    - Strategic Communications, 2004 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 4568
      Handout prepared for a CAC retreat. Handout emphasizes the importance of Communications Technical Assistance for KF communities and provides definitions, a checklist, and examples.
    - Marketing/branding of Knight Foundation, 2005-2006, 2005 September 12-2006 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 3801
      Included are two memos from Bud Meyer re: options for hiring an outside firm to assist with cohesive identity and branding of KF and the costs involved; a proposal by Frank Lane Ltd. for and memo (3/30/06) from Frank Lane Ltd. to Bud Meyer, Communications re: options and recommendations for the branding of Knight Foundation. Frank Lane recommended that KF's "core essence continue to be transformational leadership"; and that the Foundation be known as the Knight Brothers Foundation.
    - Website and redesigns, 2000 December 15-2016 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 4360
      Screen shots from launch of KF website, December 2000; memo re: Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics website; correspondence and proposals re: KF's website revision and expansion, code named, "Web 3.0". Included is a list of Web 3.0 Goals and Key Messages and Knight Foundation's Key Messages as they continue to tell the story of transformation; new website and branding launch in September 2016.
    - Webmaster Handbook, 2007 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 4569
      Handbook was updated by Robbie Adams and provides policy and procedures for communications department personnel.
    - Knight News Challenge - 2007 Promotional Campaign (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 4394
      Report prepared by Public Interest, who handled the campaign for the second year of the Knight News Challenge, which included a new website, outreach in the blogosphere and public relations. Includes figures for budgeted and actual expenses. Also included is a disc of the Public Service Announcements aired on television in 9 languages.
    - Staff Memos, 2008 July 2-2016 August 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 4386
      Includes memos on the new Knight e-newsletter; distribution of the 2008 Progress (annual) Report; announcement of the News Challenge Garage; periodic memos re: cool stuff going on at Knight; KF listing as one of "30 places we want to work" by Good Magazine; and Haitian earthquake recovery actions. Also included is a staff memo from Andrew Sherry with a reminder about email and social media policies.
    - Knight Foundation Blog, 2008 November 11-2015 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 4425
      Print out of the new in 2008 Knight Foundation Blog, which features links to KF programs, articles, reader comments, and video. Also included is a 2010 blog item on KF summer interns and copies of the blog, now called Knight Blog, beginning in June 2014. The June 10, 2015 Knight Blog features the Knight Green Line Challenge in St. Paul, MN.
    - Knight Foundation Fact Sheet, 2008-2011 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 4385
      Summary document provides highlights of the mission, programs, assets and grants of Knight Foundation. It is updated on a periodic basis. Also included is a fact sheet, entitled "Knight Foundation Talking Points for John Rogers, March 2011" lists KF assets, performance, and asset allocation and positioning.
    - Knight Foundation Message House, 2010 March 25-June 3 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 4734
      KF message: "Knight Foundation promotes informed, engaged communities. Specifically, KF advances: innovative approaches...journalism excellence... and projects that lead to transformational, sustainable change." KF employees were urged to "remember to stay inside the message house." A revised version, issued in June, is marked "For internal use only" and divides the KF message into three parts: Journalism excellence, Community engagement and Artistic excellence. Also included is a concept paper entitled, "What does an informed, engaged community look like?"
    - Mid-year Communications Report, January-June 2014 and January-June 2015, 2014 September 3-2016 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 5451
      Report highlighting media coverage for KF for the first half of 2014. Press mentions increased 18% year-on-year and KF's impact score was 2nd among 16 comparable foundations. Also, report highlighting media coverage for KF for the first half of 2015. Press mentions increased 66% from previous year and KF's media impact score increased 65% from the previous year.
    - Knight Foundation: Site Analytics Report, 2015 July (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 5573
      Report, prepared by Octopus Creative, charted how people use the existing Knight Foundation website. The purpose of the report was to gain insight into what people are searching for, and accessing, as well as where they come from. It included data from June 2014 to June 2015. It will be used to help with the planned upgrade to the KF website.
    - Mid-year Communications Report, January-June 2015, 2016 June 5 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5771
      Report highlighting media coverage for KF for the first half of 2015. Press mentions increased 66% from previous year and KF's media impact score increased 65% from the previous year.
  - Biographical Files, 1943-2017; 2.2; 2.09 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes and 1 half document box
    There are files for Advisors, Officers, Trustees and some staff members. The files contain biographical descriptions and news clippings. Creed Black's files include news releases and clippings, biographical sketches, tributes and awards, and information on his retirement party. The files on John S. and James L. Knight contain letters, magazine articles, and tributes and memorials. There is one file on the wedding of John S. Knight, Jr. The files for John S. Knight (1894-1981) include his biography by Charles Whited, Knight: A Publisher in the Tumultuous Century (New York: E.P. Dutton, 1988.) The Knight Foundation commissioned the book after John S. Knight's death in 1981. It details his life as a young journalist, publisher, and owner of a newspaper empire. Knight Foundation holds the copyright for this publication. SEE Record Group 3, Correspondence and Subject Files, Lee Hills, "Knight, John S. - Book on," for documents concerning the commissioning of this work. Also SEE, Record Group 8, Printed Materials, Reference, for reviews of Charles Whited's biography of John S. Knight, as well as clippings about John S. Knight's death in1981, and the bequest from his estate to Knight Foundation, 1981-1982.
    - Biographical Files - Advisors, 1991-2012; 2.2.1
      - Advisors-all, 1991-2012 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        Knight File Number - 240
        Biographies of Community Advisors: Reid Ashe, Roger Coover, Carrol Dadisman, John Dotson, Virginia Dodge Fielder, William Friday, James Gels, Robert Hall, Christopher Harte, Theodore Hesburgh, Harold Higgins, Lloyd Huck, Mary Junck, David Lawrence, Michael Maidenberg, Frank McComas, Scott McGehee, Heath Meriwether, James Moss, Frederick Mott, Rolfe Neill, Edmund Olson, Burl Osborne, Lewis Owens, J. Michael Pate, Dorothy Ridings, Peter Ridder, Gene Roberts, Richard Sadowski, Gerald Turner, Richard Wald, Billy Watson, Craig Wells, Roland Weeks, Clement Winke. Also includes an article on Rod Petrey, KF outside counsel and obituary of Tom Hearn, Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics chair. Included is an obituary of William Friday, former chair of the KCIA, with quotes from Alberto Ibarguen and co-chairs Brit Kirwan and Gerald Turner
    - Biographical Files - Miscellaneous, 1943-2003; 2.2.2
      - Knight, John S., Jr., 1943 November 7-2003 September 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Knight File Number - 2480